# **MICHAEL SYDNEY MOORE**

Lead Front End Developer with 4+ years of commercial experience across a range of industry sectors including medical, shipping and logistics, public sector and renewable energy. Experienced in building web and mobile apps with a focus on Typescript, React and React Native in both Waterfall and Agile development environments.

# **SKILLS**

Javascript, Typescript, Flow, HTML, CSS, React, React Native, Next.js, Preact, Storybook, Redux, Webpack, Babel, Vercel, Expo, Netlify, Datadog, Sentry, Bugsnag, TDD, Unit, Jest, Enzyme, Circle CI, Cypress

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### (August 2022 - Present) Browser London - Front End Lead

Shift OnWatch (Web App) - A platform that analyses key battery performance indicators and performance 24/7 for electric sea vessels

- Led the Greenfield build of the frontend using Typescript and React
- Worked with a dedicated UI and UX team to balance design and development timelines
- Worked with external and internal backend teams to build performant REST APIs
- Mentored junior members of the team in code standards and practices
- Implemented and led hiring practices and code tests for new members of the team
- Hired contractors and permanent staff
- Solved a very technically challenging UI problem that other developers said wasn't possible to achieve. Allowing a major client to deliver on their MVP promise to stakeholders

#### (March 2022 - August 2022) Browser London - Front End Developer

Ohealio (Web App) - A medical platform for booking consultancies and medications from gastroenterologists

- Adding detailed documentation on code practices and developer experience
- Added API documentation to make refactoring more reliable
- Introduced end to end, integration and unit tests to the Next codebase
- Refactored large parts of the Next backend that was causing production errors in payment processing
- Tested, hired and managed developers in refactoring large parts of the backend
- Fixed memory leaks that were causing slow performance in production

### (June 2020 - March 2022) M10C - Front End Developer

Balance (Mobile App) - A menopause and mental health app for women

- Led the complete refactoring of the front end React Native App.. This included migrating the existing codebase from Javascript to Typescript, updating class components to hooks, introducing ES6/7 syntax, and introducing context API to reduce the amount of API requests. Overall this led to a reduction in around 5,000 lines of code and a faster initial load time for the 500,000+ users currently using Balance

- Took the lead in converting two separate codebases into one monorepo using Webpack and React Native

- Worked with a team of backend engineers to convert all existing graphQL requests to more bespoke REST API requests. This dramatically reduced the amount of data the client sends; improving the speed of the app for the end user

WardConnect (Mobile App) - iOS and Android app for matching doctors with busy teams in hospitals

- Built the front end of the app using React Native

- Worked directly with the client to manage UI, UX and accessibility concerns relating to NHS requirements

- Built a robust test suite with TDD that increased code coverage by 45%

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

SoberApp - iOS and Android dating app for people who don't drink. Built using TypeScript, React, React Native, Expo, Mongo, Express and Node. I've also built various command line tools with Rust for automating my workflow and managing my time at work.

# **EDUCATION**

Art & Design - Central Saint Martins (2009)

### OTHER

github: https://github.com/msmfa

email: codemoore@outlook.com